Email: devmichaeldasilva@gmail.com Phone: +14073004392 Social links, website: programmedmikey.github.io

OBJECTIVE

Web development professional with over 7 years of experience designing, building, and maintaining

websites to enhance user experience, increase sales, and ensure client satisfaction. Proficient in CSS,

HTML, JavaScript, PHP, and various frameworks. Experienced in leading high-performing web

development teams and collaborating with clients to deliver exceptional results while adhering to industry

standards.

EXPERIENCE

Aug 2022 - Jun 2024

Full-stack Engineer

Dyverse

- Developed and maintained backend systems using SQL, Ruby on Rails, Docker, and managed server configurations.
- Created and integrated multiple APIs, including Google Business, Google Ads, Google Analytics, 4 (GA4), Parley, and Chatmeter.

Utilized JavaScript and HAML for front-end development and

- ensured seamless API integrations. • Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality
- software solutions and
- implemented robust testing routines

Jan 2022 - Aug 2022

App Developer

Appleton Creative

Appleton Creative Orlando, Florida

- · Designed, built and maintained several websites as well as software applications and performed website updates.
- Coordinated with a cross-functional team to resolve conflicts, prioritize needs, develop content criteria, and deliver solutions.
- Develop test routines and schedules to ensure test cases mimic external interfaces and address all browser & device types.

May 2020 - Oct 2021

Software Developer Contractor

Vijilan IT Security Remote

- Integrated multiple third-party software APIs, utilizing Lumen as the main REST API framework.
- Implemented custom features for the Partner Portal (CRM) using PHP and JavaScript within Drupal CMS.
- Ensured code quality in an Agile and SCRUM environment using a test-driven development approach

Jan 2018 - Mar 2020

Software Developer

Builderall

- Designed and developed a fully dynamic and robust Email Marketing software called MailingBoss.
- Collaborated with designers to create clean interfaces with intuitive interaction, animations, and unique features.
- Engineered automated email software with advanced analytics and performance features, leading to a significant increase in active users.

Sep 2016 - Nov 2017

Junior Web Developer **MYGSPN**

- Engineer and programmatically implement features for high school sports social media application.
- Software development tools used for the dynamic and modern web application were PHP REST API, Codeigniter, JavaScript,
- Angular 1, Ionic, Bootstrap, Database Management (MySql, SQL Server) and cloud hosting.
- · Built innovative microservices and web services REST with clear documentation, utilized by both web (Angular) and mobile (Ionic) clients.

Mar 2015 - Sep 2016

Internship Web Developer

Villa Marketers

- Website design according to Accessibility, Web Interface Usability, HTML CSS, JavaScript code validation.
- Management on various websites using HTML/CSS, bootstrap, Java script, jQuery, PHP and MySQL.
- Configuration and management of server and hosts, transfering over 40 sites from CPanel to cloud infrastructure setup with
- Ensured site usability through responsive implementation and Search Engine Optimization to improve results and business flow.

EDUCATION

Aug 2012 - Jun 2016

Bachelors of Science in Information Technology NUC University, Florida Technical College

SKILLS

- Web Development & Maintenance
- Website Testing & Troubleshooting Software Architecture
- Cloud Computing
- Coding
- Front End Framework
- DNS Management
- Back End Frameworks
- Wireframing
- Languages: CSS, CSS3, HTML, HTML5, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP, Node,, Python
- Software: Docker, FTP, SSH & CPanel, WordPress, Drupal, Dreamweaver, Illustrator
- Microsoft Office: Excel, PowerPoint, Word